William W. Hawkins Letters
William W. Hawkins Letters
1862-1865
Hawkins, William W.
9 items (SC)
Papers of the Union soldier. Civil War letters to parents and sister describing camp life and battles.
149214
Biographical History
William W. Hawkins (fl. 1862-1865) was an American soldier who fought for Union forces during the American Civil War.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William W. Hawkins Letters consist of 9 pieces of outgoing correspondence from the Union soldier to his parents and sister describing camp life and battles.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection contains one series, Correspondence, which is arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Civil War (U.S.); Military history; Hawkins, William W.; United States, Army -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Sources.; Soldiers -- United States.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Sources.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns -- Sources.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.; United States -- History, Military -- To 1900 -- Sources.; Letters (correspondence); Soldiers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 01 Jun 1862, signed holograph letter to Father, Mother, and Sister; 4 pages (Sc 254)
  - 21 Jul 1862, signed holograph letter to "Dear Folks at Home"; 5 pages (Sc 254)
  - 07 Aug 1862, signed holograph letter to "Dear Father"; 3 pages (Sc 254)
  - 09 Aug 1862, signed holograph letter to "Dear Mother"; 4 pages (Sc 254)
  - 17 Oct 1862, signed holograph letter to "Dear Father" with a one page letter to "Dear Sister Grinda" attached; 3 pages (Sc 254)
  - Nov 1862, signed holograph letter to "Father" with envelope; 4 pages (Sc 254)
  - 25 Dec 1862, signed holograph letter to "Dear Father"; 4 pages (Sc 254)
  - 25 Nov 1865, signed holograph letter; 4 pages (Sc 254)
  - undated, holograph letter to Ma; 4 pages (Sc 254)